# MARGIN PATEL

Address: 14 Sparrow Court, Brampton, ON

Email: margin.patelh@gmail.com, (647-909-9084)
Portfolio: https://margin98.github.io/simplefolio/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/margin-patel-79b48b129/

### **Summary**

I am enthusiastic in developing custom responsive websites. My professional goal is to work as a Full-Stack Web Developer. I've worked with a variety of programming languages, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Asp.Net, Angular, React, and others. I am also proficient in relational databases. Can create, build, and query databases. Experienced with a range of applications such as VS Code, NetBeans, Visual Paradigm, and Eclipse. Ability to troubleshoot and resolve issues with hardware, software, and network connectivity.

### **Technical Skills**

- Back-end: Java, C#, C, Node.
- Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, Spring Boot, React.
- Database Management Systems: SQL, MySQL, Talend.
- **Development Tools:** Android Studio, Visual Studio code, Eclipse, NetBeans, Microsoft Office, Adobe XD, Git.

### **Experiences**

Front-end software developer – Shopify Theta Techno labs Ahmedabad, Gujarat, INDIA Mar 2019 - Oct 2019

- Maintained and updated customer websites as needed.
- Participated in weekly mentoring sessions with web developers within the organization.
- Discuss options with clients to make sure websites meet their needs as well as the needs of their customers.
- Customization and building of e-commerce websites.
- Managing many online stores on the Shopify platform.
- Performed weekly assessments of all websites and software to look for potential problems or crashes.

Application Developer
Theta Techno labs (Internship CO-OP)
Ahmedabad, Gujarat, INDIA

Jul 2018 - Mar 2019

- Under supervision, provide entry-level professional services as appropriate to the dayto-day operating objectives of the area. Receives guidance, training, and mentoring from senior personnel in planning and carrying out activities and assignments.
- Undertake and/or participates in projects and programs designed to develop professional skills and expertise appropriate to the needs of the organization.

- Responsible for support and assist development team in design and development of web and mobile applications using android studio tool.
- Integrate data from various back-end services and databases. Working on the database (SQL) to fix the data issues.
- Support many different tasks, including software programming, maintenance, analysis, and user support in the functional areas of training systems, infrastructure and tools development using C/C++, Java, PHP languages along with web technologies.

## **Education**

**UDEMY ONLINE SCHOOL** 

Jan 2022 - May 2022

Major: Web Developer Course By ZTM

Skills Learned: React, Redux, Node.JS, Express, SQL, JavaScript, Visual Studio Code

#### **DIPLOMA | SHERIDAN COLLEGE**

**Sept 2020 – Dec 2021** 

**Major: Computer Programmer** 

**Skills Learned:** Mobile Application Development, Web Development, Windows App Development (C#), Java, MySQL, Linux.

#### **BACHELORS | CPICA (GUJARAT UNIVERSITY)**

Jun 2016 – Mar 2019

**Major: Computer Applications** 

**Skills Learned:** SQL, Microsoft Office, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures, Java, .Net, PHP, Android studio, C++.

### **Projects**

#### Event Expert (Android Application)

- Android App Designed, developed, and published a new android application called "Event Expert" for Android tablets and mobile phones. Worked with APIs to connect to 3rd party platforms such as Facebook and Amazon web services.
- Tools and technologies that I used in this application is Android studio, Java, PHP and MySQL database.
- This application is developed for a user who is searching for an event in a particular area, and they can participate in the event and see event nearby location and its information using this app. They can also create their own events.
- Created first design of this application using adobe XD.

#### Pet Rescue charity (Database)

- In this project, we helped the fictional organization Pet Rescue Charity with managing their donations data.
- This project's goal was to upload the list to a Central Donation Repository. Task is ETL the process from SQL Server to Oracle, Donation list loading, Created Star schema, loading of star schema, created view and Security.
- Used SQL developer and Talend in this project.